<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking Archives Blog</title>
    <link>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Networking Archives Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Lazy Person&#39;s Network Analysis Workflow</title>
      <link>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2021/04/15/my-network-analysis-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2021/04/15/my-network-analysis-workflow/</guid>
      <description>The Networking Archives project is using tools from other disciplines to write histories of seventeenth-century intelligencing and correspondence. Key in the toolset for the project is network analysis. Network analysis is a suite of tools developed to understand and analyse networks, specifically, network graphs, a formal term for a mathematical graph of entities, known as nodes, connected by vertices, or edges.
There are tonnes of tools available for converting data into a network format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracing Itineraries in the State Papers</title>
      <link>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/archive/tracing-itineraries-in-the-state-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/archive/tracing-itineraries-in-the-state-papers/</guid>
      <description>This is an R Notebook: a document containing code and text. The source code is available in a GitHub repository: download the folder and then open it with R-Studio to run the notebook yourself. You’ll need a little bit of prior knowledge of R and the tidyverse to properly follow along. This post is the second in a series documenting some of the code and techniques we’ve been using on the Networking Archives project: you can read the first one, looking at Wikidata, here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women in the State Papers Online - Through the Data</title>
      <link>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/archive/women-in-the-state-papers-online-through-the-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/archive/women-in-the-state-papers-online-through-the-data/</guid>
      <description>You can’t search for women in the State Papers Online. There’s no way of knowing how many letters they wrote, or received, or how often they were mentioned. If you know the name you’re looking for you can search through the descriptions and abstracts, but you would need to watch out for spelling variants or mistakes. This method also doesn’t help estimate how many letters there are overall, and it limits the possibility of the chance discovery of women’s writing in the archive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Calendars of State Papers with Word Vectors</title>
      <link>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/archive/representing-calendars-of-state-papers-with-word-vectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/archive/representing-calendars-of-state-papers-with-word-vectors/</guid>
      <description>Text and Models What can a body of text tell us about the worldview of its authors? Many Digital Humanities projects involve constructing models: a general name for a kind of representation of something which makes it in some way easier to interpret. TEI-encoded text is an example of a model: we take the ‘raw material’ of a document, its text, and add elements to it to make it easier to work with and analyse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Mining the State Papers</title>
      <link>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2021/04/14/text-mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2021/04/14/text-mining/</guid>
      <description>Calendars of State Papers and Networking Archives Most of the quantitative research on the Networking Archives project has been using the metadata from the digitised correspondence of State Papers Online. Metadata in this sense means everything except the content of the letters: including author names, recipient names, date, place of sending and so on, in the research of seventeenth-century intelligencing. Gale State Papers Online brings together a number of historical primary sources, not only the manuscript images from the State Papers, but also full text versions of the ‘Calendars of State Papers’, a set of printed finding aids mostly produced in the nineteenth century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R and Wikidata</title>
      <link>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2021/02/15/r-and-wikidata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2021/02/15/r-and-wikidata/</guid>
      <description>This is an R Notebook: a document containing code and text. A live version can be run through MyBinder, which will spin up a copy of R-studio for you to use, and the source code is available on GitHub.
Clicking on the MyBinder link above will bring you to an R-Studio instance. In the ‘files’ window in the bottom-right of R-studio, open the document ‘r_and_wikidata.Rmd’, which will open this with a live copy of the code, which can be edited and re-run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>‘Networking Archives’ is a three-year, AHRC funded research project which will merge the early modern correspondence data collected in ‘Early Modern Letters Online’ with metadata from the ‘Gale State Papers Online’ to create thereby the UK’s largest meta-archive of curated early modern correspondence metadata.
The resulting dataset and accompanying infrastructure will allow researchers to interrogate and analyse epistolary metadata on an unprecedented scale and to pose new kinds of questions on the history of ‘intelligencing’ from the 16th to 18th centuries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
