<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Networking Archives Blog</title>
    <link>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Networking Archives Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Co-Citation Networks from Letter Mentions: A Short Guide</title>
      <link>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2021/05/13/co-citation-networks-from-letter-mentions-a-short-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2021/05/13/co-citation-networks-from-letter-mentions-a-short-guide/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Community Detection in a large academic co-citation network. A link is drawn (as a grey line) between two authors (as coloured circles) if they are both cited in the same paper. Data from: https://www.aminer.cn/citation  This is an R Notebook: a document containing code and text. The source code is available in a GitHub repository. Download the folder and then open it with R-Studio to run the notebook yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the State Papers with Word Embeddings</title>
      <link>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2021/04/26/exploring-the-state-papers-with-word-embeddings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2021/04/26/exploring-the-state-papers-with-word-embeddings/</guid>
      <description>Text and Models Digital Humanities is often concerned with creating models of text: a general name for a kind of representation of text which makes it in some way easier to interpret. TEI-encoded text is an example of a model: we take the raw material of a text document and add elements to it to make it easier to work with and analyse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Mining the State Papers</title>
      <link>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2021/04/19/text-mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2021/04/19/text-mining/</guid>
      <description>Calendars of State Papers and Networking Archives Most of the quantitative research on the Networking Archives project has been using the metadata from the digitised correspondence of State Papers Online. Metadata in this sense means everything except the content of the letters: including author names, recipient names, date, place of sending and so on, in the research of seventeenth-century intelligencing. Gale State Papers Online brings together a number of historical primary sources, not only the manuscript images from the State Papers, but also full text versions of the ‘Calendars of State Papers’, a set of printed finding aids mostly produced in the nineteenth century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Lazy Person&#39;s Network Analysis Workflow</title>
      <link>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2021/04/15/my-network-analysis-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2021/04/15/my-network-analysis-workflow/</guid>
      <description>The Networking Archives project is using tools from other disciplines to write histories of seventeenth-century intelligencing and correspondence. Key in the toolset for the project is network analysis. Network analysis is a suite of tools developed to understand and analyse networks, specifically, network graphs, a formal term for a mathematical graph of entities, known as nodes, connected by vertices, or edges. Mostly they boil down to either specific software packages with a GUI, such as Gephi or Palladio, or dedicated libraries within a coding language such as Python’s NetworkX or R’s Igraph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women in the State Papers Online - Through the Data</title>
      <link>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2021/04/15/women-in-the-state-papers-online-through-the-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2021/04/15/women-in-the-state-papers-online-through-the-data/</guid>
      <description>You can’t search for women in the State Papers Online. There’s no way of knowing how many letters they wrote, or received, or how often they were mentioned. If you know the name you’re looking for you can search through the descriptions and abstracts, but you would need to watch out for spelling variants or mistakes. This method also doesn’t help estimate how many letters there are overall, and it limits the possibility of the chance discovery of women’s writing in the archive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R and Wikidata</title>
      <link>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2021/02/15/r-and-wikidata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2021/02/15/r-and-wikidata/</guid>
      <description>This is an R Notebook: a document containing code and text. A live version can be run through MyBinder, which will spin up a copy of R-studio for you to use, and the source code is available on GitHub.
Clicking on the MyBinder link above will bring you to an R-Studio instance. In the ‘files’ window in the bottom-right of R-studio, open the document ‘r_and_wikidata.Rmd’, which will open this with a live copy of the code, which can be edited and re-run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking Archives publication in Computational Humanities Research</title>
      <link>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2020/11/17/networking-archives-publication-in-computational-humanities-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2020/11/17/networking-archives-publication-in-computational-humanities-research/</guid>
      <description>The Networking Archives project is reconciling three separate datasets—Early Modern Letters Online, the Tudor State Papers Online, and Stuart State Papers Online—into one meta-archive. One commonality between the three is that they all, to some degree, contain missing and partial data—potentially a source of anxiety when we come to consider the veracity of our findings. In a recent paper authored by some of the project team, presented at the first Computational Humanities Research Workshop, we outlined some strategies for dealing with missing data, and argued that perhaps we shouldn’t be so worried after all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Networking Archives Fellows Yann and Philip</title>
      <link>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2020/05/05/new-networking-archives-fellows-yann-and-philip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://networkingarchives.github.io/blog/2020/05/05/new-networking-archives-fellows-yann-and-philip/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to introduce two new members to the Networking Archives team: Yann Ryan and Philip Beeley. They joined us as Fellows earlier this year, and will be undertaking key parts of the collaborative research projects that we have scoped, including co-authoring the project ‘multigraph’ with the rest of the team, and co-editing the collection of essays coming out of the training schools.
Yann recently completed a PhD thesis ‘Networks, Maps and Readers: Foreign News Reporting in London Newsbooks, 1645 – 1649’ (QMUL), which looked at the flow of news from overseas to London, and examined how this can be traced and measured using computational techniques (including network analysis) as well as more traditional scholarly methods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
